Amlan Banaji

Curriculum Vitae

Website: amlan-banaji.github.io

Email: afb8 "at" st-andrews.ac.uk

PhD student in Mathematics at St Andrews

Nationality: UK

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am primarily interested in the geometry and dimension theory of fractal sets and measures. I have worked with fractals generated by conformal and non-conformal iterated function systems. Much of my research has focused on interpolating between different notions of dimension. I am interested in finding connections between fractal geometry and other areas of mathematics.

PUBLICATIONS AND PREPRINTS

- 1. Attainable forms of intermediate dimensions (with A. Rutar) Annales Fennici Mathematici 47 (2022) 939–960. arXiv
- 2. Intermediate dimensions of infinitely generated attractors (with J. M. Fraser) To appear in **Transactions of the American Mathematical Society**. arXiv
- 3. Metric Spaces where Geodesics are Never Unique *To appear in the American Mathematical Monthly. arXiv*
- 4. Intermediate dimensions of Bedford–McMullen carpets with applications to Lipschitz equivalence (with I. Kolossváry)
 Submitted. arXiv
- 5. Assouad type dimensions of infinitely generated self-conformal sets (with J. M. Fraser) *Submitted. arXiv*
- 6. Generalised intermediate dimensions *Submitted*. *arXiv*

EDUCATION

University of St Andrews

2019–present

PhD Mathematics (in progress)

Topic: Fractal geometry and dimension theory

With the **Analysis Research Group**

Supervisors: Prof. Jonathan Fraser (primary), Prof. Kenneth Falconer

Fully funded by the **Leverhulme Trust**

University of St Andrews

2018-2019

MSc Mathematics, Distinction

GPA: 19.5/20. Ranked 1st in the Faculty of Science and Medicine

Dissertation:

<u>Solvability of Partial Differential Equations on Fractal Domains</u> (Score: 19.1/20, supervised by <u>Professor Kenneth Falconer</u>)

University of Cambridge,

King's College 2015–2018

BA (Hons) Mathematics

Selected Part II courses: Linear Analysis, Analysis of Functions, Topics in Analysis, Differential Geometry, Riemann Surfaces, Logic and Set Theory

Thomas Tallis Sixth Form

2013-2015

A-Levels:

Mathematics(A^*), Further Mathematics(A^*), Physics(A^*), Chemistry(A^*), History(A), Extended Project Qualification(A^* , equivalent to half an A level)

SELECTED PRIZES

2019: **Postgraduate Gray Prize** for the best MSc student in the Faculty of Science and Medicine at the University of St Andrews.

TALKS

I have given 20 talks (listed at amlan-banaji.github.io/talks) at conferences and seminar series including:

- Szenzhen Technology University Mathematics Colloquium, (China (online), inaugural talk, 22/10/22)
- Fractals and Related Fields IV (Porquerolles, France, 5/9/22)
- Geometry of Deterministic and Random Fractals (Budapest University of Technology and Economics, 30/6/22)
- Junior Ergodic Theory Meeting (ICMS, Edinburgh (30/3/22) and online (19/3/21))
- Workshop on affine and overlapping iterated function systems (Bristol, 11/5/22)
- Dynamics and Group Geometry Early Researchers Seminar (DAGGER) (Warwick, 30/5/22 and 1/3/21)
- Analysis Seminar (St Andrews, 3/5/22, 12/10/21, 20/4/21, 30/6/20)

EXPERIENCE

Teaching undergraduate tutorials at the University of St Andrews:

Most recent student feedback score: 1.5 on a scale from 1 to 5 (where 1 is highest).

2019–2022: MT2502 Analysis (10 groups total)

2021: MT2505 Abstract Algebra (2 groups)

2020: MT1003 Pure and Applied Mathematics (2 groups)

- *2018–present:* **Tutoring** mathematics (undergraduate, A level and STEP) with G5 Education, Oxford Exclusif Tutorial Agency, PhD Tutors, Sishu Chinese School, and privately.
- 2018: LMS-funded **Cambridge Summer Research in Mathematics (SRIM) project** on Leray-Schauder Topological Degree Theory and its applications to Partial Differential Equations.
- 2017: internship at market research company Kantar TNS, working as a **data scientist** for the social media team, using Python.

SERVICE

- 2022: **Referee** for *Proc. Roy. Soc. Edinburgh Sect. A* and *J. Math. Anal. Appl.*
- 2022: **Organiser** of St Andrews Analysis Reading Group
- *2021*: **Co-organiser** of the Postgraduate Interdisciplinary Mathematics Symposium (PIMS), St Andrews.
- 2019–2021: **Treasurer** of St Andrews Mindfulness Society.

MEMBERSHIP OF PROFESSIONAL BODIES

- 2022–present: London Mathematical Society
- 2020–present: Edinburgh Mathematical Society
- 2019–present: Institute of Mathematics and its Applications

INTERESTS AND SKILLS

- **Languages:** English (native), German (conversational, A* at GCSE), Hindi (conversational)
- Music: Piano (grade 8), Clarinet (toured Canada and Venice)
- **Sport:** running, badminton, chess